Guide to the Robert H. Elias papers, 1933-1983.
Elias, Robert H. papers, 1933-1983.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert H. Elias papers, 1933-1983.
14-12-1848
Robert H. Elias
.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, memoranda, conference agendas, notes, news releases, and reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, memoranda, conference agendas, notes, news releases, and reports of Robert Henry Elias, with particular reference to the American Studies Society, the American Historical Association, and the American Civilization Graduate Club.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of English, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, memoranda, conference agendas, notes, news releases, and reports of Robert Henry Elias, with particular reference to the American Studies Society, the American Historical Association, and the American Civilization Graduate Club. Correspondents and subjects include Harold Loeb, Marion Cummings, Bedelia Croly Falls, e. e. cummings, Saul Bellow, James Gould Cozzens, John Dos Passos, Katherine Anne Porter, Edmund Wilson, Jerome Kern, Huey Long, Henry Miller, Lewis Mumford, Frank O'Connor, John Crowe Ransom, James Thurber, Richard Wilbur, Theodore Dreiser, H. L. Mencken, and Toni Morrison.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Elias, Robert H.; Loeb, Harold, 1891-1974.; Bellow, Saul.; Cummings, Marion.; Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962.; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990.; Falls, Bedelia Croly.; Cozzens, James Gould, 1903-1978.; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970.; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1890-1980.; Wilson, Edmund, 1890-1972.; Kern, Jerome, 1885-1945.; Long, Huey Pierce, 1893-1935.; Miller, Henry, 1891-; Morrison, Toni.; O'Connor, Frank, 1903-1966.; Ransom, John Crowe, 1888-1974.; Thurber, James, 1894-1961.; Wilbur, Richard, 1921-2017.; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Bellow, Saul; Cozzens, James Gould, 1903-1978; Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962; Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945; Kern, Jerome, 1885-1945; Loeb, Harold, 1891-1974; Long, Huey Pierce, 1893-1935; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956; Morrison, Toni; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990; O'Connor, Frank, 1903-1966; Porter, Katherine Anne, 1890-1980; Ransom, John Crowe, 1888-1974; Thurber, James, 1894-1961; Wilbur, Richard, 1921-2017.; Cummings, Marion; Falls, Bedelia Croly; Miller, Henry, 1891-; Wilson, Edmund, 1890-1972; American Studies Society.; American Historical Association.; American Civilization Graduate Club.; Cornell University -- Faculty.; American Historical Association; Cornell University
Subjects:
Study skills; Universities and colleges -- Faculty
Places:
United States -- Study and teaching.; United States
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Marion Cummings Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Marion Cummings, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bedelia Croly Falls, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Harold Loeb, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- American Historical Association, 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- American Civilization Graduate Club, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Saul Bellow, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- James Gould Cozzens, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- e.e. cummings, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- To George Allen & Unwin, Ltd., 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- To John Dos Passos, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Mrs. Matthew Josephson, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- To Bernhard Kendler, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- To Katherine Anne Porter, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- To Edmund Wilson, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence received, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Epoch Magazine, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Herbert E. Gaston, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- William Gibson, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Robert Silliman Hillyer, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Jerome Kern, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Bernhard Kendler, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Huey Long, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 17-19)
- Henry Miller, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Lewis Mumford, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- The Nation, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Frank O'Connor, c. 1954 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Harriet O'Connor, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Katherine Anne Porter, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 25-27)
- John Crow Ransom, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Susannah Tarkington, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Helen Thurber, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 30-31)
- James Thurber, 1944-1958 (Box 2, Folder 32-36)
- Richard Wilbur, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Theodore Dreiser (including Richard Lingeman and Robert Fleissner correspondence), 1937-1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- H. L. Mencken, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Toni Morrison, 1953, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- John Dos Passos: One Man's Initiation: 1917; Layout, printing proofs, publishing correspondence, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
- John Dos Passos and others: correspondence, 1918-1968 (Box 3, Folder 7-17)